

#### CONTACT

- www.giftegwuenu.com
- Lagos, Nigeria

#### **EDUCATION**

### BACHELOR OF SCIENCE: COMPUTER SCIENCE

2015

Houdegbe North American University Cotonou, BN

## SKILLS & EXPERTISE

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue, React, Webpack, GraphQL, Jamstack, Node.js, SQL, Gridsome, Technical Writing, Adobe XD

#### SOCIAL



@lauragift

<u>@lauragift</u>

# GIFT EGWUENU

Frontend Engineer & Technical Writer

#### **ABOUT**

Gift is a frontend engineer and technical writer based in Lagos Nigeria. She's passionate about making the web accessible to everyone and also an advocate for building open-source projects. She enjoy solving complex problems using web technologies and she's a big advocate for building open and inclusive communities which led me to start the Vue Vixens chapter in Nigeria and the JAMstack community in Lagos. She's a co-organizer of the Concatenate Conference, a Media Developer Expert at Cloudinary, and an Auth0 Ambassador.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONTEND DEVELOPER & DEVELOPER EVANGELIST

Datopian | March 2020 - Present

- Designed and developed client facing user interfaces.
- Communicated with clients and designed UI mockups.
- Worked closely and interacted with the Frictionless Data Community via (chats, remote hangouts, and in-person events)
- Wrote documentation, guides and blog posts for Frictionless Data

#### **CONTENT STRATEGIST**

Ruby Together | Mar 2020 - Present

 Responsible for writing and publishing monthly updates to RubyGems Blog.
 Maintaining existing documentation and writing new guides (RubyGems/Bundler docs).

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Andela | Aug 2018 - Mar 2020

- Responsible for building and deploying interactive web application using front end technologies.
- Collaborate excellently with peers and stakeholders in fast-paced distributed team.

#### **OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTOR**

Rekkur Solutions | Jan 2018 - Dec 2018

- Worked with a diverse and remote team to help build features for a Hugo Custom
  Thomas
- Created relevant issues and fixes for Hugo based Theme (Syna)

#### **SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

Hirefreehands.tech | July 2017 - Mar 2018

- Worked with a team of software developers to design and develop scalable platform for the company
- Maintained product quality by building and implementing new feature.